HANIYEH FATHOLAHI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email: haniyeh.fath@gmail.com

Location: Dortmund, North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/h-fatholahi

Website: itishannuk.github.io



SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with 5 years of work experience in medium-sized and large companies providing software solutions in the fields of intelligent transportation, fleet tracking, payment and insurance systems. Having worked in these companies, I am skilled in system analysis, design and backend development.

My expertise is now to design and develop applications and systems using Java and NodeJS including their related frameworks, technologies and tools such as different databases - SQL and NoSQL databases. In addition, experienced in developing IoT based services using IoT brokers or WebSocket like management and communication services. It is worth mentioning that I am interested in microservice architecture and cloud software development.

EXPERIENCES

MAY 2021 - MAR 2022

JAVA DEVELOPER IN INSURANCE CORE INSURANCE, DOTIN, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Contributed to design and develop the system new service, legal insurance
- Designed and implemented legal insurance rest APIs
- Refactored 100% of the code for annual insurance branch performance report in order to increase reusability
- Refactored several financial features in order to improve performance and reusability
- Designed and implemented marketers reporting dashboard
- Improved WebSocket notification service memory consumption by tunning the configuration of the message broker and refactoring the existing code

OCT 2016 - FEB 2021

R&D DEPARTMENT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MAGFA, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Developed fleet tracking services for GPS tracking systems containing about 3000 online tracker devices
- Optimized performance by using multithreading and queuing
- Designed and implemented Rest APIs for fleet tracking applications and services
- Collaborated with Frontend team in order to upgrade frontend technologies
- Designed and developed a USSD Wrapper service for USSD based mobile payments

SEP 2016 - MAR 2020

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TOOBATECH, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Technical lead of Toobatel Instant messaging system project for Alzahra university
- Designed and implemented 100% chatting system in Toobatel app using MQTT brokers
- Designed and implemented Toobatel bot engine in order to integrate student services
- Designed and implemented backend services based on customers' requirement

SKILLS

	Solid Understanding	Worked With	Familiar with
Programming languages	Java, NodeJS	JavaScript	Typescript
Development tools/frameworks	Spring framework - Spring boot – Hibernate - Express JS - Maven	JPA – jUnit - Swagger	Gradle
Software engineering & methodologies	OOP – Agile – Scrum - System design	Design Patterns – GIT - CI/CD - Unit Testing	DDD
Architecture	Microservice - MVC	SOA	
Web technologies	RESTful APIs – SOAP Webservices – JSON - XML		
Development and deployment tools	IntelliJ idea – Eclipse – Webstorm – Postman - SQL developer	Docker - Apache tomcat – VerneMQ – RabbitMQ – Apache - Nginx – jConsole - jMeter	Kubernetes - Jenkins - Kafka
Databases	Oracle – MySQL – MongoDB - Redis	Neo4j – PostgreSQL - Cassandra	
os	CentOS - Fedora - Windows	Ubuntu	
Project/Source control	GitLab – Bitbucket - Jira	Trello	

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, ALZAHRA UNIVERSITY, TEHRAN

Dissertation Title: "implementing IoT platform by customizing Openstack cloud computing Infrastructure APIs for collecting metrics from IoT nodes."

CERTIFICATES

- Oracle Database 12c administration, LAITEC institute of Sharif University of Technology, Tehran
- Java 8 Standard Edition, LAITEC institute of Sharif University of Technology, Tehran

LANGUAGES

- Persian: Native
- English: Fluent (TOEFL iBT certificate C2)
- German: Basic (taking in A2 level classes)